The final data type we will cover for now is the
bool data type, short for Boolean. Boolean values
are either true or false or, in binary terms,
1 or 0. I have a code example, 114-boolean,
that shows a Boolean variable on line 1,
char_life, which is set to True. Part of learning
a programming language is learning the nuances
of its syntax. In most programming languages,
the words true and false represent Boolean values.
Notice that the True and False values on lines 1
and 3 are title-cased, meaning they start with
capital letters. Python is case-sensitive in
many spots, including this one. It is important
to learn these characteristics to use the correct
casing for Boolean variables and avoid errors when
trying to run code containing them. To see the
results of this code, which returns a value based
on the status of a character's life for a game,
I will run the code, and the code works,
showing that I am still in the game. However,
it fails if I change True to lowercase true and
try to rerun this code. We do see a message asking
us if we meant to use the title-cased version
of the word, True, at least. To finish this
unit on data types and operators, I will switch
to this file, 114-analyze, and here we have five
print statements that display types for various
pieces of data. Go to your workbook and do the
“Review 1.1” project to identify the data types
of each piece of data as a string, integer, float,
or boolean. In the next video, we will reveal
and discuss the answers to the workbook project.